Program manager here at the ESS high school,
on our social science program.
In my program responsibility I plan schedules,
service distribution, structures around meetings
and I am a link between students, teachers
And all staff and principals.
My name is Carina Backström and working as
Swedish teacher at high school.
My name is Emelie Sköld, I'm a teacher at
The ESS high school in Swedish, and is also a mentor
in a grade one class.
The biggest challenge in working with
Pupils with NPF is about emptying one
on energy, that they are so intense.
It's all or nothing, in everything.
While it is a challenge,
that is both tough and positive, that they think
outside the box.
That one all the time yourself
All the time, it's not always that simple.
Something that is important is that today's teachers are
Extremely flexible.
One cannot do a planning
And think that it should be followed to the point.
That's not the important thing.
The important thing is to
Students come to learning.
And maybe they were
Takes other ways than I had imagined.
But it does nothing, rather the opposite.
It is about activating them, that actually
Boll back, start discussions, get with
them in that "what do you want for something?"
At the beginning of the autumn term we always have one
In-calls, enrollment calls, where we almost
interviewing the student, about what it feels
That it needs.
It may be about that
have to go out of the classroom shorter periods,
double sets of teaching materials, that one
want things to work with, with your hands
At the same time as you have a lesson.
We'll find out
Very much through these in calls.
What conditions we have to work with
and how we can develop together,
by being in the classroom.
By the whole
Time with my way of being sets boundaries,
shows what is ok, dialogue, make it become
Lusty and fun.
So the most important bit
In the learning environment, it is the teacher.
We have made a number of adjustments of it
physical learning environment as well, the one that one pure
Krassst can see, as part of our NPF fuse.
Things we've done is that we have big,
clear watches in the corridors and
in the classrooms for it to be easy to
Keep track of time.
We have made sure it is
neutral and colors that are connected to
The school, so it should be calm impressions.
We have sofas in the corridors that are sound attenuated.
When one sits in there it is like a small
Koja, it's really nice to sit in there.
We have clear markings of where halls and
Expedition is there so it should be easy to
Find for the students.
Often when talking about making adjustments
Do you think of everything you can't do,
and we have tried to turn it around and see what we have,
Which is positive.
This is an old school
built in the 60s, with long corridors,
quite small classrooms, and there are none
Structure is, as I said, very important for those
Here the students and we work with a
Color coding system here.
That means we have
Color coded, for example, you have Swedish
so it is red on the schedule, and so you have a
red cover and a red sticker on it
Teaching materials used.
So then they can just look;
"Red, then I bring the red with me".
It demands
not so much, they don't have to waste energy
On reading and looking, without they can only find it.
Very practical!
I try to create structure by using
PowerPoints that are clear, with which lesson
And where we are.
Clear start-up, clear end of the lesson-
much with the help of the structure we have on the board
But also checklists with what we will
do today, so they get the confirmation that
We have moved on.
And time-timers, that
We decide that we should have a review in
Ten minutes and then I can't go on
Talk, but then it's time to move on.
So it is also part of our structure.
As for the teaching, it is
very important that when you have had a review,
Then I know which students may
Have lost focus.
Directly up to them,
asks “are you with now, look here, we'll start here,
do this ". You might make special schedules for
Some students, "Do you know, do these three tasks now,
The hand I come and help you ”.
When students get longer jobs that maybe
should last for a while it is important to help
The student to stay focused all the way.
That man
can do as an educator is partly that one has
reconciliations.
They may work maybe two lessons,
then man gathered and has a reconciliation-
"How's it going, how are you located, what do you need to think
on now? ”If they work independently you have
maybe reconciliation with a student- “Ok, you are
here, remove that and do this. "So that
one all the time is with them on the way to
the goal and all the time point to it as they have
succeeded with.
We try not to have homework in that sense.
Take advantage of.
So the idea is that they should not
have to take home lots of school work.
Not everyone has
the same conditions to plug at home.
Some need to rest and do something completely different
to recover for the next day.
I adapt my teaching by
try to be varied both on length and
on content.
Review preferably no longer
than a quarter, many people can't listen more than that.
But also vary work tasks,
orally or in writing, group work or
Individual work.
For it to fit like that
Throughout the organization should understand what, for example
NPF means.
What we do to npf-secure our school is
That we constantly have our NPF glasses on us.
It's about looking at the physical
the learning environment, how we post our lessons,
It is about organization, about response,
And it's about knowledge.
I would
say is the basis of everything for through
knowledge you gain understanding, and otherwise it is
easy to do you to do lots of things without knowing
one ends with it too because one does not
Understand the purpose of that.
So it's all about
That knowledge provides understanding.
Then the next step is what to do with it
Here the knowledge and it is the difficult part.
How to put up our structure, our schedule
and our entire arrangement at this school,
according to the needs of the students.
At our school we ensure the NPF knowledge
in the staff by having repeated
lectures, literature spreads, we encourage
me how to handle concentration difficulties,
But this student that I have in my class,
Nothing works.
Whatever I do, I reach
not that student ". And we should be able to talk that
About and meet around.
Here at the ESS Gymnasium we work in Duo
meaning that we are always two teachers in
the classroom and through that I have learned
Very much about these students.
We can
Always check ideas and find different solutions.
At this school I can get extremely good support
As for students with NPF.
Partly I have
My team where we work a lot with this.
We talk all the time and help each other.
We support each other because it is sometimes tough.
Great school management, one can go in and piss
And get help.
You can ask for guidance.
We have an NPF educator who can guide one.
The absolute most fun thing about my job that does
that I, sometimes when it is heavy or that
rains and i'm tired and can't, it
is still to get to school and meet
These amazing students.
Get to work with them